Guide to the Stanford University, Department of English, Publications
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of English, publications
1902-1961
1902-1917
SC4-3881
Stanford University. Department of English.
2 Linear feet
Collection includes 5 bound volumes of syllabi from rhetoric and literature courses (primarily English literature), 1907-1917, 6 bound volumes of briefs from debate classes, 1902-1921, and one folder on the freshman English class, 1960-61. The debate briefs include statement of the resolution, references, outline of argument, and conclusion. Typical topics include interstate commerce, railroads, marriage laws, foreign policy, labor, capital punishment, immigration and treatment of immigrant populations (particularly Japanese and Chinese), liquor laws, the single tax, and child labor. There were some debates on issues specific to Stanford, including policy of the student affairs committee, removing saloons in vicinity of Stanford, abolishing final examinations, the "Major Subject" system, intercollegiate athletic contests, tuition fees in engineering and profession courses, football reform, and co-education.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes 5 bound volumes of syllabi from rhetoric and literature courses (primarily English literature), 1907-1917, 6 bound volumes of briefs from debate classes, 1902-1921, and one folder on the freshman English class, 1960-61. The debate briefs include statement of the resolution, references, outline of argument, and conclusion. Typical topics include interstate commerce, railroads, marriage laws, foreign policy, labor, capital punishment, immigration and treatment of immigrant populations (particularly Japanese and Chinese), liquor laws, the single tax, and child labor. There were some debates on issues specific to Stanford, including policy of the student affairs committee, removing saloons in vicinity of Stanford, abolishing final examinations, the "Major Subject" system, intercollegiate athletic contests, tuition fees in engineering and profession courses, football reform, and co-education.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Stanford University. Department of English.; Debates and debating.; English literature --Study and teaching (Higher).
Collection Contents
- Syllabi
  - 1907-1909, 1 volume(s)
  - 1909-1911, 1 volume(s) (Box 1)
  - 1911-1912, 1 volume(s) (Box 1)
  - 1912-1914, 1 volume(s) (Box 2)
  - 1914-1917, 1 volume(s) (Box 2)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Syllabi of Oral Debate
  - 1902-1904, 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
  - 1904-1906, 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
  - 1906-1908, 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
  - 1909-1910, 1 volume(s) (Box 4)
  - 1913-1915, 1 volume(s) (Box 4)
- Enlgish 32 Briefs, 1920-1921; 1 volume(s) (Box 4)